export const topick2 = [
  {
    question:
      'What was the name of the famous sailor from Ostend who circumnavigated the globe in the 17th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Jan de Van',
      b: 'Pieter de Nepture',
      c: 'Klaas van Wist',
    },
    answer: 'Pieter de Nepture',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which sailor from Ostend explored the coast of Africa in the 15th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Lambert de Gerter',
      b: 'Jan van Ruisdael',
      c: 'Hendrik Everaert',
    },
    answer: 'Hendrik Everaert',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who was the captain of the first ship of the Ostend Company?',
    options: {
      a: 'Willem Ruyten',
      b: 'Karel van Gent',
      c: 'Maarten de Los',
    },
    answer: 'Karel van Gent',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which famous admiral from Ostend participated in the Battle of Lepanto?',
    options: {
      a: 'Cornelis de Witt',
      b: 'Jan Pieterson',
      c: 'Gerard van Leuven',
    },
    answer: 'Cornelis de Witt',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which Ostend sailor opened new trade routes to Asia in the 18th century?',
    options: {
      a: 'Willem de Graaf',
      b: 'Jacob van Schep',
      c: 'Adriaan de Clerck',
    },
    answer: 'Jacob van Schep',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which captain from Ostend first crossed the Atlantic on a merchant ship?',
    options: {
      a: 'Lambert van Osten',
      b: 'Herman de Witt',
      c: 'Klaas Jansen',
    },
    answer: 'Lambert van Osten',
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which sailor from Ostend is known as the 'father of the Belgian navy'?",
    options: {
      a: 'Jan van Dijk',
      b: 'Pieter Kuiper',
      c: 'Adriaan Hendricks',
    },
    answer: 'Pieter Kuiper',
  },
  {
    question:
      'What was the name of the Ostend sailor who first reached Antarctica?',
    options: {
      a: 'Karel van Houten',
      b: 'Lambert van Osten',
      c: 'Hendrik de Vries',
    },
    answer: 'Hendrik de Vries',
  },
  {
    question: 'Which Ostend sailor was awarded the French Legion of Honor?',
    options: {
      a: 'Jan van Burg',
      b: 'Pieter de Groot',
      c: 'Cornelis de Jong',
    },
    answer: 'Pieter de Groot',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which famous captain from Ostend participated in the Battle of Trafalgar?',
    options: {
      a: 'Lambert van Dijk',
      b: 'Jan de Witt',
      c: 'Herman van Leuven',
    },
    answer: 'Jan de Witt',
  },
];
